Edalat Feizi

Android Developer

Iran, +98 919 542 4221, edalat.feizi@outlook.com, https://www.linkedin.com/in/edalatfeizi/

Experienced software engineer with +5 years of developing native Android applications in agile teams.

Solid understanding of mobile software development life cycle, design patterns, UI/UX, and Scrumban.

Have a successful track record of developing and maintaining high-quality Android applications.

Love learning new technologies and new challenges.

Skills

Programming languages: Java, Kotlin

IDE & Software: Android Studio, Postman, Trello

Standards: Material Design, Jetpack Compose

Databases: SQLite, Room, Firebase

Architecture & Design patterns: MVC, MVP, MVVM, CLEAN

Essentials: Scrum, Kanban, Git, GitHub, Retrofit, Dagger

Work History

2022-03 Current Android Developer

Freelance, Alborz

Redesigned an online second-hand goods application, to increase its maintainability, performance, and robustness.

- Restructuring applications with the help of the latest architectural patterns
- Writing unit tests and integration tests to make sure different features working as expected
- Implementing UI components with Jetpack Compose instead of XML Layouts to increase performance

Tech Stack: Kotlin, Room, JUnit, Mockito, Hilt, Jetpack Compose

2021-07 – 2022-02 Senior Android Developer

Fanavari Hooshmand Kaj, Alborz

Working in an agile team of talented and eager-to-learn developers and designers made me an opportunity to know different aspects of software development and also let me mentor other junior team members to help them make better products.

- Worked with a small team of mobile developers to implement the redesign of the existing crypto exchange app based on Clean Architecture to make a testable, maintainable and scalable application.
- Fixed bugs and improved application performance.
- Wrote unit tests for mobile code and debugged critical application issues such as crashes, memory leaks, and concurrency problems.

Tech Stack: Kotlin, Clean Architecture, Dagger, Live Data, Retrofit, JUnit

2020-06 – 2021-07 Senior Android Developer

Arina Hoosh Abzar Kish, Alborz

Developed multiple apps including a Car rental app, Shopping App, sports club app for fans of San Pablo Burgos club

- Developed Android apps based on architectural patterns including (MVP/MVVM).
- Created reusable and robust codes to make apps faster and smoother on devices with limited resources.
- Developed custom views for reusable components.

Tech Stack: Java, Kotlin, Coroutines, Room, Live Data

Arina Hoosh Abzar Kish, Alborz

- Collaborating with team members in an agile environment to plan and deliver products on time
- Developed Android applications using Java and Kotlin programming languages
- Worked on the compatibility of the applications with different types of devices

Tech Stack: Java, Kotlin, Retrofit, Dagger, FCM, Google Map

Education

2013-09 – 2015-06 Bachelor's Degree, Computer Software Engineering
Ghiasodin Jamshid Kashani Higher Education Institute, Qazvin

2011-02 – 2013-06 Associate's Degree, Computer Software Engineering
Shahid Babaei Technical College, Qazvin

Languages

Azerbaijani Native
Persian Native

English Intermediate